# Georg J.P. Link

orcid.org/0000-0001-6769-7867

#### **SUMMARY**

My research advances our knowledge in corporate engagement with open source projects. As corporate involvement increases, open source foundations provide guidance and support for open source projects. We only begin to understand the evolution of this triangular relationship. My current research focus is to inform this relationship through research into open source project health and new market mechanisms. My work has been accepted to the Communications of the Association for Information Systems, the Journal for Universal Computer Science, ACM GROUP, Americas Conference on Information Systems, OpenSym, HICSS, CHAOSSCon, INFORMS, and MWAIS. My research has been supported by the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, Mozilla, and the Linux Foundation.

I am engaged at both professional and university levels. I volunteered at various academic conferences, was a conference co-organizer for the 2017 Big XII+ MIS Symposium, am currently the Communications Chair for AIS SIGOPEN, and am an active member of the University of Nebraska at Omaha's BRIDGE Lab — a lab dedicated to the advancement of IT design, architecture, and education. I have reviewed for ICIS, AMCIS, MWAIS, ECIS, PACIS, HICSS, and OpenSym. Finally, I am an active member in the Linux Foundation CHAOSS project and the Mozilla Bugmark project.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA

■ Ph.D. in Information Technology	planned 2019
Thesis: Signaling Theory in Collaborative Environments	

- Advisor: Prof. Matt Germonprez
- Focus: Open Source Community Health

# MBA – Master of Business Administration Concentration: Collaboration Science

• Cumulative GPA: 3.9 / 4.0

## Technical University Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany

- M.S. in Business Informatics 2014
  - Thesis: Evaluating Anchored Discussion as a New Tool for Creativity in Online Collaboration
  - Cumulative GPA: 1.3 (German grade translates to 3.7 / 4.0)

#### WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany

- B.A. in Business Administration 2011
  - Concentration: Banking
  - $\bullet\,$  Cumulative GPA: 1.8 (German grade translates to 3.2 / 4.0)

#### **GRANT FUNDING** Total: \$9,459.00

- \$700.00 Linux Foundation 2018
  - Travel support to Open Source Summit North America, Vancouver, Canada
- \$2,441.00 Mozilla 2018
  - Travel support to ACM Collective Intelligence, Zurich, Switzerland
- \$1,318.00 Linux Foundation 2017
- Travel support to Open Source Summit North America, Los Angeles, CA, USA
- \$5,000.00 University of Nebraska at Omaha 2017
  - Program: Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA)
  - Proposal title: The Changing Nature of Volunteerism in Open Source Communities

### **SCHOLARSHIPS**

- Hanns-Seidel-Stiftung 2012 2014
- German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD) 2012 2013

# HONORS & AWARDS

- Doctoral Student Service Award, Association for Information Systems 2017
- Best Paper Award, AIS SIG GlobDev
  - Link, G. J.P., & Qureshi, S. (2017). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. In *Proceedings of the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems*. Boston.
- Above and Beyond Excellence Award from UNO Student Government 2013
- Rotary Youth Leadership Award (RYLA) Seminar 2008

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **JOURNALS (2)**

- [2] Link, G. J.P., K. Lumbard, K. Conboy, M. Feldman, J. Feller, J. George, M. Germonprez, S. Goggins, D. Jeske, G. Kiely, K. Schuster, M. Willis (2017). Contemporary issues of open data in Information Systems research: Considerations and recommendations. *Communications of the Association for Information Systems*, *41*(Article 25), 587–610. http://aisel.aisnet.org/cais/vol41/iss1/25/
- [1] Link, G. J.P., D. Siemon, G. de Vreede, S. Robra-Bissantz (2016). Anchored Discussion: Development of a Tool for Creativity in Online Collaboration, *Journal for Universal Computer Science*, 22(10), 1339–1359. https://doi.org/10.3217/jucs-022-10-1339

#### **CONFERENCES (13)**

- [13] Link, G. J.P., & Germonprez, M. (2018). Assessing open source project health. In Twenty-fourth Americas Conference on Information Systems 2018 Proceedings. New Orleans, LA.
- [12] Rao, M., Link, G. J.P., Marti, D., Leak, A., & Bodo, R. (2018). A trading market for prices in peer production. In ACM Collective Intelligence 2018 Proceedings. Zurich, Switzerland.
- [11] Rao, M., Link, G. J.P., Marti, D., Leak, A., & Bodo, R. (2018). A Trading Market to Incentivize Secure Software. In 17th Annual Workshop on the Economics of Information Security (WEIS), Innsbruck, Austria. https://weis2018.econinfosec.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/5/2016/09/WEIS\_2018\_paper\_27.pdf
- [10] Gandhi, R., Germonprez, M., & Link, G. J.P.\* (2018). Open data standards for open source software risk management routines: An examination of SPDX. Presented at the ACM GROUP'18, Sanibel Island. https://doi.org/10.1145/3148330.3148333
  - [9] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, & Qureshi, S. (2018). The role of open source communities in development: Policy implications for governments. Presented at the HICSS 2018, Hawaii. http://hdl.handle.net/10125/50190
  - [8] Link, G. J.P. (2017). The value of engaging with open source communities. In *OpenSym '17 Companion*. Galway, Ireland: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3126673.3126679
- [7] <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> & Jeske, D. (2017). Understanding organization and open source community relations through the Attraction-Selection-Attrition Model. In *OpenSym '17 Companion*. Galway, Ireland: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3125433.3125472
- [6] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, & Qureshi, S. (2017). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. In *Proceedings of the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems*. Boston. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2017/ICTs/Presentations/18/
- [5] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Gill, J., & Khazanchi, D. (2017). Measuring adoption of open source software and practices in organizations: A pilot study. In *Proceedings of the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference*. Springfield, IL. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/mwais2017/43/
- [4] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Lumbard, K., Germonprez, M., & Goggins, S. (2017). Advancing open online community science practice: The open community data exchange. In *Proceedings of the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference*. Springfield, IL. http://aisel.aisnet.org/mwais2017/44
- [3] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Germonprez, M., Goggins, S., Hemsley, J., Rand, B., & Squire, M. (2016). The Open Community Data Exchange: Advancing data sharing and discovery in open online community science. In *OpenSym '16 Companion*. Berlin, Germany: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/2962132. 2962142
- [2] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, & Germonprez, M. (2016). Understanding open source communities as complex adaptive systems: A case of the R Project community. In AMCIS 2016 Proceedings. San Diego, CA. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2016/Open/Presentations/7/
- [1] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Siemon, D., de Vreede, G.-J., & Robra-Bissantz, S. (2015). Evaluating Anchored Discussion to Foster Creativity in Online Collaboration. In N. Baloian, Y. Zorian, P. Taslakian, & S. Shoukouryan (Eds.), Collaboration and Technology (pp. 28–44). Springer International Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-22747-4\_3

<sup>\*</sup>Authors in alphabetical order

#### **OTHER PUBLICATIONS (1)**

[1] Ahuja, V., Marti, D., Link, G. J.P., Germonprez, M., & Goggins, S. P. (2018, May 23). How to measure the impact of your open source project. Retrieved May 23, 2018, from https://opensource.com/article/18/5/metrics-project-success

#### PRESENTATIONS (13)

- [13] Link, G. J.P. (2018, March). Engaging Volunteers and Voluntolds in Open Source Projects. Presented at the 10th Annual Research and Creative Activity Fair, University of Nebraska at Omaha, NE, USA. https://digitalcommons.unomaha.edu/srcaf/2018/schedule/148/
- [12] Germonprez, M., & Link, G. J. P. (2017, September). BoF: Community Health Analytics for Open Source. Birds-of-a-Feather presented at the Open Source Summit North America, Los Angeles, California. Retrieved from http://sched.co/BCsP
- [11] Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). Understanding organization and open source community relations through the Attraction-Selection-Attrition Model. Presented at OpenSym 2017, Galway, Ireland.
- [10] Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). The value of engaging with open source communities. Presented at the OpenSym 2017 Doctoral Consortium, Galway, Ireland.
- [9] Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. Presented at the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems, Boston, MA.
- [8] Link, G. J.P., & Lumbard, K. (2017, May). Advancing open online community science practice: The open community data exchange. Presented at the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference. Springfield, IL.
- [7] Link, G. J.P. (2017, May). Measuring adoption of open source software and practices in organizations: A pilot study. Presented at the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference. Springfield, IL.
- [6] Link, G. J.P. (2016, December). Moving Open Source Communities: How Foundations Onboard Communities. Presented at the SIGOPEN Developmental Workshop at ICIS 2016, Dublin, Ireland.
- [5] Link, G. J.P., & Lumbard, K. (2016, December). Communication Technology Selection in a Young Open Source Community: A Case of the Hyperledger Project. Presented at the SIGOPEN Developmental Workshop at ICIS 2016, Dublin, Ireland.
- [4] Link, G. J.P. (2016, August). The Open Community Data Exchange: Advancing Data Sharing and Discovery in Open Online Community Science. Presented at the OpenSym 2016, Berlin, Germany.
- [3] Link, G. J.P. (2016, April). The Guided Evolution of Open Source Communities. Presented at the 14th Annual BigXII+MISResearchSymposium, Baylor University, Waco, TX, USA.
- [2] Link, G. J.P. (2016, March). The Guided Evolution of Open Source Communities. Presented at the 8th Annual Research and Creative Activity Fair, University of Nebraska at Omaha, NE, USA. http://digitalcommons.unomaha.edu/srcaf/2016/Schedule/56/
- [1] Link, G. J.P. (2015, November). The Movement and Commoditization of Open Source Communities. Presented at the INFORMS Annual Meeting 2015, Philadelphia, PA, USA.

#### ACADEMIC APPOINTMENTS

#### University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA

Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant

2015 – present

- Funded by Alfred P. Sloan Foundation
- Funded by Mozilla

#### WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany

Visiting Lecturer for Information Systems

2014 – present

### Technical University Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany

Research Assistant

2014 - 2015

- Institute of Business Information Systems Information Management Group
- Research and Teaching Assistant

2013 - 2014

 Institute of Operating Systems and Computer Networks Algorithms Group

	<ul> <li>Institute of Business Information Systems         Decision Support Group     </li> </ul>	
GRANT WRITING EXPERIENCE	NSF: Early-concept Grants for Exploratory Research (EAGER) Title: Securing Critical Software Through Futures Markets; PI: Matt Germonprez; Unfunded propos	2018 al.
	Mozilla Research Grants 2018H1  Title: Experiment on Introducing Project Health Signals and Price Signals in Open Source; PI: Georg	2018 g Link; Under review.
	Mozilla Open Source Experiments Program  Title: Experiment for Health Signals in Bugmark; PI: Georg Link; Unfunded proposal	2018
	<b>Alfred P. Sloan Foundation</b> Title: Open Source Project Health and Sustainability; PI: Matt Germonprez and Sean Goggins; (2018-2020)	2017 Funded with \$449,351
	<b>GRACA</b> internal grant University of Nebraska at Omaha Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA); Title: The Changing Nature of Volunte Communities; PI: Georg Link; Funded with \$5,000 (2017)	2017 erism in Open source
	<b>GRACA</b> internal grant University of Nebraska at Omaha Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA); Title: The Guided Evolution of Open Source C Link; Unfunded proposal.	2016 Communities; PI: Georg
	<b>BMBF</b> (German Federal Ministry of Education and Research) Title: DETHIS - Design Thinking for Industrial Services; PI: Christoph Lattemann; Project number (1.6 million Euro (2016-2019).	2014 2017 2015 2016 2016 2016 2016 2016 2016 2016 2016
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	Managing the Database Environment University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA	2017 – 2018
	<b>Organizations, Applications, and Technology</b> University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA	2017
	Introduction to Microsoft Excel WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany	2014 – Present
PROFESSIONAL	UNO Mozilla Campus Club, University of Nebraska at Omaha	
UNIVERSITY	■ Founder and Vice-President	2018 – Present
ACTIVITIES	Graduate College Committee, University of Nebraska at Omaha	
	■ Student Representative	2016 – 2018
	UCRCA Committee (internal grants), University of Nebraska at Omaha	
	■ Student Representative	2016 – 2017
	PhD Student Group, University of Nebraska at Omaha	
	■ Founder and President	2015 – 2017
PROFESSIONAL	Executive	
ACADEMIC	<ul> <li>Communications Director, AIS SIGOPEN</li> </ul>	2015 – Present
ACTIVITIES	Organizing (Conference and Workshop)	
	OpenSym Program Committee	2018
	<ul> <li>AMCIS Minitrack Co-Chair</li> <li>Minitrack: Peer Production Project Health</li> </ul>	2018
	<ul><li>OpenSym Program Committee and Session Chair</li><li>SIGOPEN Pre-ICIS Workshop on Open Phenomena</li></ul>	2017 2017
	Reviewing for Journals	
	<ul> <li>2018</li> <li>Information and Organization</li> <li>Information Technology for Development</li> <li>Journal of Organizational Computing and Electronic Computers</li> </ul>	2018
	<ul> <li>Journal of Organizational Computing and Electronic Commerce</li> <li>2017</li> </ul>	2017

■ Research Assistant

2011 - 2012

	<ul> <li>Information Technology for Development</li> <li>Information &amp; Management</li> <li>International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Small Business</li> <li>International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction</li> <li>2016</li> <li>Communications of the Association for Information Systems</li> </ul>	2016
	Reviewing for Conferences  2018: ICIS, AMCIS, OpenSym 2017: AMCIS, ECIS, PACIS, MWAIS, OpenSym 2016: ICIS, HICSS, AMCIS, ECIS 2015: ECIS	2018 2017 2016 2015
	<ul> <li>Conference Volunteering</li> <li>ACM Group</li> <li>OpenSym</li> <li>Big XII+ MIS Research Symposium</li> <li>International Conference on Information Systems</li> <li>International Conference on Web Intelligence and International Conference on Brain Informatics &amp; Health</li> <li>Coalition of Urban and Metropolitan Universities</li> </ul>	2018 2017 2017 2016 2016
PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS	<ul> <li>Association for Information Systems (AIS)</li> <li>AIS SIGOPEN</li> <li>Midwest United States Association for Information Systems (MWAIS)</li> </ul>	2016 – Present
	Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)	2016 – Present
	<ul> <li>Participated in Open Source Projects</li> <li>CHAOSS Project</li> <li>Core Infrastructure Initiative Best Practices Badge</li> <li>Toolkit for YNAB</li> <li>Drupal</li> <li>OpenOffice.org</li> </ul>	2006 – Present
INDUSTRY TRAINING & CERTIFICATES	<ul> <li>Bankkaufmann</li> <li>Certified by Chamber of Commerce, Braunschweig, Germany</li> <li>Bankhaus C. L. Seeliger, Wolfenbüttel, Germany</li> </ul>	2008 – 2011
	<ul> <li>Ausbilder-Eignungsprüfung</li> <li>Certified by Chamber of Commerce, Braunschweig, Germany</li> <li>WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany</li> </ul>	2011
REFERENCES	<ul> <li>Matt Germonprez</li> <li>Mutual of Omaha Associate Professor</li> <li>Information Systems and Quantitative Analysis</li> <li>University of Nebraska at Omaha</li> <li>mgermonprez@unomaha.edu</li> </ul>	
	<ul> <li>Sean Goggins         Associate Professor         School of Information Science and Learning Technologies         University of Missouri         s@goggins.com     </li> </ul>	
	■ Brian Dorn Associate Professor Computer Science University of Nebraska at Omaha bdorn@unomaha.edu	

# ■ Robin A. Gandhi

Associate Professor Cybersecurity University of Nebraska at Omaha rgandhi@unomaha.edu



[CV last updated on 2018-07-04]